[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我们有一个日期函数，它的灵感来自于Java的日期
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: We have a date function which was inspired by Java's Date
类，它在1995年引入时还没有准备好Y2K。
class, which was not Y2K ready when it was introduced in 1995.
我不知道他们是不是认为语言会围绕这一点
I don't know if they didn't think the language was going to be around that
如果他们没有预见到它的到来或者交易是什么。
long or if they didn't see it coming or what the deal was.
但我们挺过来了。
But we survived it.
万岁，而且它已经被修复了，所以我们得到了它。
Hooray, and it's been fixed, so we got that.
我们得到了从Perl4借用的正则表达式。
We got regular expressions which were borrowed from Perl 4.
这是一个与正则表达式文字匹配的正则表达式文字。
This is a regular expression literal that matches regular expression literals.
这就是我所说的，我讨厌这个大会的地方是
That's what I claim, the thing that I hate about this convention is that
如果有一个长度超过一英寸或两英寸的正则表达式，它是
if you have a regular expression that's longer than an inch or two, it's
真的很难有任何信心它包含你认为它包含的东西，
really hard to have any confidence that it contains what you think it contains,
以便它匹配或拒绝您认为它将匹配和拒绝的内容。
so that it matches or rejects what you think it will match and reject.
我承认我写了几英尺长的正则表达式文字
And I will confess I've written regular expression literals that are several feet
很久了，我并不以此为荣。
long and I am not proud of that.
但是语言并没有让它变得容易，因为
But the language doesn't make it easy to do because
它们都必须被卷在一起。
they all have to be scrunched together.
你甚至不能在它们中使用空格来分隔元素
You can't even use whitespace in them to kind of separate the elements so
你可以看到它在做什么。
you can see what it's doing.
和所有的粉碎在一起，这几乎是不可能的
And all smushed together, it's virtually impossible for
人类来破译那是什么。
human to decipher what that is.
幸运的是，网络上有一种叫做Regulex的东西。
Fortunately, there is something on the web called Regulex.
然后给Regulex一个正则表达式文字，然后
And you give a regular expression literal to Regulex and
它将为您提供正则表达式的铁路图。
it will give you a railroad diagram of what that regular expression does.
所以你可以看到它的作用
So you can see what it does and
你可以很好地理解它的行为。
you can have a good understanding of how it will behave.
我不会在不运行它的情况下编写另一个正则表达式
I will not write another regular expression without running it
通过Regulex
through Regulex.
强烈推荐。
Highly, highly recommended.
是吗？&gt；&gt；扬声器2：查找
Yeah? &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Find
你自己写的正则表达式太长了，
yourself writing a regular expression that's too many inches long,
你能拿一根小一点的绳子吗？&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：可以，
can you just get a smaller string? &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah,
谢谢你。&gt；&gt；观众：[笑]
thank you for that. &gt;&gt; Audience: [LAUGH]
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：我必须这样做，对不起。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: I had to, sorry.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：不，你不必这样做。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No you didn't have to.
&gt；&gt；观众：[笑]
&gt;&gt; Audience: [LAUGH]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以你可能
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So you're probably
想知道好的部分什么时候开始。
wondering when do the good parts start.
我还没有听到任何好的部分。
I haven't heard any good parts yet.
函数，函数是最好的部分，我们将在下个小时讨论这些。
Functions, functions are the good part and we'll talk about those in the next hour.
所以在JavaScript中，除了null和undefined之外，所有的值都是对象。
So in JavaScript all values are objects except null and undefined.
这些就是有时所说的最低值。
These are what are sometimes called bottom values.
对于一种语言是否应该有任何底值，存在一些争论。
And there's some debate as to whether a language should have any bottom values?
在这个问题上没有争论，一种语言应该有两个底值吗？
There's no debate on the question, should a language have two bottom values?
答案是绝对没有，这没有任何意义。
The answer is absolutely not, that doesn't make any sense.
但我们有两个。
But we have two.
他们的行为很相似，但他们的行为并不完全相同，所以
And they act a lot alike but they don't act exactly alike, so
它们不能互换。
they're not interchangeable.
但有些人可以互换使用，这是一种混乱，
But some people use them interchangeably which is a confusion,
混乱会导致错误，我不喜欢这样。
confusion causes bugs, I don't like that.
所以我建议只使用其中的一个，我选择使用的那个
So I recommend using only one of them and the one I choose to use
是未定义的，因为它是语言本身使用的，但是
is undefined because that's the one that the language itself uses, but
它们都用于表示不是对象的值。
both of them are used to represent values that are not objects.
这些是语言中唯一不是对象的值。
These are the only values in the language that are not objects.
所以如果你试图从其中一个中检索一个值，你将不会得到任何东西。
So if you try to retrieve a value from one of these, you're not gonna get anything.
如果您尝试将它们作为函数执行，它们将抛出异常。
If you try to execute them as functions, they'll throw exceptions.
它们只是用来表示某事的缺席或结束。
They're just used to indicate the absence or the end of something.
所以我建议使用undefined。
So I recommend using undefined.
选择Undefined，因为它是语言本身使用的语言。
Choose undefined because it is the one that the language itself uses.
所以如果我只用一种语言，那就把语言作为一种语言来使用。
So if I'm only gonna use one, let's use the language as one.
所以它是变量和参数的默认值。
So it's the default value for variables and parameters.
因此，如果您创建了一个变量，但没有对其进行初始化，
So if you create a variable but you don't initialize it,
它实际上是用未定义的值为您初始化的。
it actually gets initialized for you with the undefined value.
如果您有一个函数，但没有传递足够的参数，
And if you have a function and you don't pass enough arguments in,
缺少的参数将绑定到undefined。
the missing parameters will get bound to undefined.
它是缺少对象和数组成员的值。
It's a value of missing members of objects and arrays.
因此，他试图检索一个属性或元素，但它不在那里。
So he tried to retrieve a property or an element and it isn't there.
您不会得到运行时警告，也不会得到编译时警告。
You don't get a runtime warning, you don't get a compile time warning.
相反，您得到的是未定义的值，这实际上是一件非常好的事情。
Instead, you get the undefined value which is actually a very nice thing.
因为它可以让你毫不费力地思考物体，
Because it allows you to reflect on objects without any effort,
你刚刚问了，你得到了其中一个，如果你得到一个值
you just asked, you got one of those and if you get a value back and
你得到了什么，或者如果你没有，那么你没有。
you got something or if you didn't, then you didn't.
但需要注意的一件事是，您可以将未定义的存储到对象中，并且
One thing to watch out for though is that you can store undefined into an object and
然后你可以读回未定义的内容，但是
then you can read that undefined back but
你不能很容易地说，我得到了一个未定义的，存储在对象中或者
you can't easily tell, I'm I getting an undefined that was stored in the object or
我得到一个未定义的，因为它没有存储在对象中？
I'm getting an undefined because it wasn't stored in the object?
他们看起来都一样。
They both look the same.
这是一种混淆，我不喜欢混淆。
That's a confusion, I don't like confusion.
JavaScript中有一种类型的运算符，它将返回一个字符串
There's a type of operator in JavaScript which will return a string
识别某物的类型。
identifying what the type of something is.
例如，如果您向它传递一个对象，它将返回一个String对象，这很棒。
For example, if you pass it an object, it returns a string object which is great.
你给它传递一个函数，它会返回一个很好的单词function。
You pass it a function, it returns the word function which is great.
如果向它传递一个数组，它将返回不是
If you pass it an array, it returns object which is not
技术上是错误的，因为所有东西都是对象，但肯定没有用处。
technically wrong because everything is an object but it's certainly not useful.
您希望它返回数组，因为它就是这样。
You'd like it to return array because that's what it is.
所以，但是如果你传递它否，它返回对象是错误的。
So, but if you pass it no, it returns object which is just wrong.
这是没有借口的。
There's no excuse for that.
它并不会使检测某物是否为空变得困难
It doesn't make it hard to detect if something is null
因为只有一个NULL值，所以你可以问，你是三倍等于NULL吗？
because there's only one null value, so you can ask, are you triple equal to null?
非常有效。
That's very effective.
问题是，你试图弄明白，你是一个物体吗？
The problem is, you're trying to figure out, are you an object?
因为如果你不是一个物体，我下一步就不想尝试某些东西。
Because if you're not an object there are certain things I don't want to try next.
这个测试失败了，这真的，真的很糟糕。
And this test fails for that, which is really, really bad.
所以我们现在有Array.isArray，
So we have Array.isArray now,
它是在ES5中添加到语言中的。
it was added to the language in ES5.
虽然它看起来非常丑陋，但它最终还是允许
While it's extremely ugly looking it does finally allow
我们来检测某个值是否是数组，这是很好的。
us to detect if some value is an array or not, which is good.
这就是它在旧浏览器上的实现方式。
And this is how it is implemented on older browsers.
JavaScript是一种boolish语言，因为每个值都是真的或假的。
JavaScript is a boolish language in that every value is truthy or falsy.
错误的值是false，null，undefined，
The falsy values are false, null, undefined,
空字符串、数字0和NaN。
the empty string, the number 0, and NaN.
所有其他价值都是真实的。
All other values are truthy.
包括字符串0，字符串false，所有对象，
Including the string 0, the string false, all objects,
所有数组，即使它们是空的，所有这些都是真实的。
all arrays even if they're empty, all those are truthy.
我认为这是一个巨大的错误。
I think this was a huge mistake.
这样做的目的是允许if语句起作用
The purpose of this was to allow if statements to work
在某种程度上类似于C的工作方式。
in a way that's similar to the way C works.
C不是强类型语言。
C is not a strongly typed language.
所以它用0来代表数字0，而FALSE，
And so it uses 0 to represent the number 0, and false,
和NULL以及其他一些东西，
and null and a few other things,
字符串的结尾，我相信还有很多其他的。
end of strings, I'm sure there are lots of others.
因此，C中IF语句的条件是0或不是0，并且
So the condition of an if statement in C is 0 or not 0, and
JavaScript想要看起来像这样，但结果却是一个糟糕的主意。
JavaScript wanted to look like that but it turns out to be a bad idea.
我们明天会看到一些例子。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：JavaScript
We'll see some examples of that tomorrow. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: JavaScript
是一种松散类型的语言，因为这些类型中的任何一种都可以存储在任何变量中
is a loosely typed language in that any of these types can be stored in any variable
或者作为参数传递给任何函数。
or passed as a parameter to any function.
语言不是无类型的，因为正如我们所看到的，我们有很多非常具体的
The language is not untyped because as we had seen we've got a lot of very specific
类型，但它是松散类型的。
types but it's loosely typed.
我认为这是一个很好的部分，尽管这句话非常
And I contend this is a good part and although that statement is very
有争议的是世界上流行的风格呼唤
controversial the prevailing style in the world is calling for
强类型和强类型有很好的论据。
strong typing and there are really good arguments for strong typing.
其论点是，强类型允许编译器及早发现错误。
The argument is that strong typing allows the compiler to find errors very early.
我们越早发现错误，就越有价值。
And the earlier we can find errors, the more valuable that is and that is true.
所以当我第一次开始使用JavaScript时，我非常，
And so when I first start working with JavaScript, I was very,
非常紧张，因为这是一种松散类型的语言，
very nervous because this is a loosely typed language,
任何类型都可以作为任何参数传入或存储在任何属性中。
any kind of type can be passed in as any parameter or be stored in any property.
你怎么能有信心任何事情都会成功，
How could you have any confidence that anything's ever gonna work,
因为在任何时候都要为任何事情做好准备是很疯狂的。
cuz gotta be prepared for anything at any time was crazy.
但我在使用这种语言的过程中发现，令我惊讶的是，
But what I found in working with the language was that to my surprise,
我的测试负担没有增加，好吗？
my testing burden did not go up, all right?
我以为我要看着所有这些东西
I thought I was gonna have to be watching for all of these things and
放入我自己的显式类型检查，我很少这样做。
putting in explicit type checks of my own, and I very rarely ever had to do that.
事实上，我发现的是
And in fact, what I found was that the sorts of bugs that
类型检查器可以找到，如果您正在做的话，您可以立即找到
a type checker can find, you find instantly anyway if you're doing
即使是最微不足道的测试，这些东西也会马上出现。
even the most trivial level of testing, those things show up right away.
这种类型的系统在以下方面没有提供帮助
That type systems provide no help in
找到让你夜不能寐的虫子。
finding the bugs that keep you up at night.
最后你做的工作会少很多，因为在一个强大的
And that you end up doing a lot less work because in a strongly
类型化语言你最终会花费大量的时间来对抗类型系统。
typed language you end up spending a lot of time working against the type system.
为了完成你的工作，你需要做一些事情
There are things you need to do in order to get your job done and
类型系统不希望你做这些事情。
the type system doesn't want you doing those things.
所以你必须想办法绕过它，这是很大的努力。
And so you have to figure out ways to get around it and that's a lot of effort.
无论何时进行强制转换，这都意味着类型系统不能满足您的要求。
And any time you cast then that means the type system is failing you.
结果你投的太多了。
And you end up casting way too much.
此外，事实证明，有一大类错误是由类型引起的
Also it turns out there is a large class of errors which are caused by the type
系统。
system.
因为类型系统导致您绕过它，
Because the type system is causing you to circumvent it,
你最终做了很多额外的工作，其中一些工作变成了bug。
you end up doing a lot of extra work and some of that work turns into bugs.
而在JavaScript中，这种情况往往不会发生。
And in JavaScript that tends not to happen.
所以我发现用JavaScript编写正确的程序并不比用Java难，
So I find in JavaScript writing correct programs is not harder than in Java,
我觉得这实际上更容易。
I think it's actually easier.
而且你做的工作少了很多，因为你不是一直都在管理所有的类型，
And you do a lot less work because you're not managing all the types all the time,
这就是我的论点。
that's my argument.
您可能不相信我，如果您正在使用JavaScript get编写，这并不重要
You might not believe me, and it doesn't matter if you're writing in JavaScript get
习惯了因为这就是它的工作原理。
used to it because that's how it works.
所以在JavaScript中，对象是通过引用传递的
So in JavaScript, objects are are passed by reference
不是按值，这意味着不复制对象。
not by value which means that objects are not copied.
事实上，在JavaScript中没有办法，也没有简单的方法来制作对象的副本
In fact, there is no way, no easy way in JavaScript to make a copy of an object
这似乎是一个令人惊讶的遗漏，但是
which seems like a surprising omission but
在实践中，我没有发现这是一个问题。
in practice I've not found it to be a problem.
=运算符比较对象引用，因此
The === operator compares object references so
只有当两个操作数是相同的对象时，它才会给出true。
it'll give you true only if both operands are the same object.
没有简单的测试，是两个非常相似的物体，
There is no easy test for, are two objects very similar,
包含相同的属性，具有相同的值？
containing the same properties, having the same values?
这又一次，似乎是一个奇怪的遗漏，但我没有发现这是一个问题。
That again, seems like a strange omission, but I've not found that to be a problem.